Helen Stuart Whitehead collection, circa 1914-1919 (bulk 1917-1918
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Helen Stuart Whitehead collection 1914-1919 (bulk 1917-1919)
MS 453
Whitehead, Helen Stuart
The Helen Stuart Whitehead collection consists of photographs and pamphlets relating to the University of Arizona compiled during Ms. Whitehead’s tenure as a student 1914-1919.
1 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Biographical Note
Helen Stuart Whitehead was born on Sept.5, 1897 in Indianapolis, Indiana to the parents of Mr. and Mrs. Herbert L. Whitehead, she had two brothers and two sisters. In the years of 1916-17 Miss Helen S. Whitehead attended Butler College (Indianapolis, Indiana). While attending college at the University of Arizona Helen S. Whitehead was the Hiking Captain in 1918-1819, s, she was Chairman for West College (1918-20). She also was Secretary and Treasurer of her Senior Class. Helen S. Whitehead also was part of PI Beta Phi Sorority. She also took 3units of a correspondence class while here in Tucson, Arizona. Helen S.Whitehead graduated with a B.S in Home Economics in the year 1920.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 2 series.
Series I: Pamphlets,1917-1918
Series II: Photographic Material,circa 1914-1919
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of pamphlets and photographic materials. Collection includes 3 pamphlets from University of Arizona in 1917-1918. The photographs include various photographs of Arizona, campus views, events, and people.
Access Terms
Whitehead, Helen Stuart, 1897-
University of Arizona--History--Photographs
Education Building--(Tucson, AZ)--Photographs
West Cottage (Tucson, AZ)—Photographs
Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Pamphlets, 1917-1918
  This series contains 3 various University of Arizona pamphlets
  - University of Arizona pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Photographic Materials, 1914/1919">1914-1919
  This series contains various photographs in no particular order
  - Arizona Views, circa 1914-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Education building, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Campus Views, circa 1914-1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Groups and friends, circa 1914-1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Groups and friends, circa 1914-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Helen S. Whitehead, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - West Cottage group photos, circa 1914-1919 (Box 1, Folder 8)